<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>policy on Chas Nelson</title>
    <link>/categories/policy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in policy on Chas Nelson</description>
    <image>
      <url>cjn.jpg</url>
      <link>cjn.jpg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 20:19:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/policy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Standing up for Science</title>
      <link>/posts/the-little-eye/standing-up-for-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 20:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-little-eye/standing-up-for-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I attended the Sense about Science &lt;a href=&#34;#sas&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; media workshop: Standing up for Science &lt;a href=&#34;#workshop&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;. The day is run as part of their Voice of Young Science network &lt;a href=&#34;#voys&#34;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; and aims to help early career scientists launch themselves into the rather intimidating field of media engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop itself was a really interesting day so thanks to Chris Peters and Ana Skamarauskas for organising and chairing through the day. It was primarily composed of three very interactive panels: scientists who have communicated with the media, journalists who work in STEM-related media, and the &amp;rsquo;nuts and bolts&amp;rsquo; panel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of UK Life Sciences</title>
      <link>/posts/the-little-eye/future-of-uk-life-sciences/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 18:00:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-little-eye/future-of-uk-life-sciences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month the House of Lords Science and Technology Select Committee, which scrutinises Government policy relating to science and technology, announced an inquiry into the future of UK life sciences &lt;a href=&#34;#lsis&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;. This is off the back of the Government&amp;rsquo;s Industrial Strategy Green Paper &lt;a href=&#34;#industry&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; and aims to investigate, amongst other things, whether or not the Government has the infrastructure to support an innovative life sciences sector in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As somebody with a passion for bioimaging I thought I might stress the importance of bioimaging and similar supporting technologies. Without technologies such as bioimaging and next generation sequencing, the UK biosciences and bioeconomy would not be the innovative and world-class scene that it is. So, here it is, my two pence worth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
