<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>research on Chas Nelson</title>
    <link>/categories/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in research on Chas Nelson</description>
    <image>
      <url>cjn.jpg</url>
      <link>cjn.jpg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Event-based Super-resolution Microscopy</title>
      <link>/posts/project/event-driven-super-resolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/project/event-driven-super-resolution/</guid>
      <description>Using novel event-based sensors to improve the speed of super-resolution microscopy. &lt;a href=&#34;/project/event-driven-super-resoluton/index.html&#34;&gt;Read more&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neuronal Graphs</title>
      <link>/posts/project/neuronal-graphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/project/neuronal-graphs/</guid>
      <description>Using graph theory and network science to understand the brain. &lt;a href=&#34;/project/neuronal-graphs/index.html&#34;&gt;Read more&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very Fast Volumetric Microscopy</title>
      <link>/posts/project/event-driven-volumetric/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/project/event-driven-volumetric/</guid>
      <description>Using novel event-based sensors to improve the speed of light sheet fluorescence microscopy for very fast volumetric imaging. &lt;a href=&#34;/project/event-based-volumetric/index.html&#34;&gt;Read more&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive Prospective Optical Gating</title>
      <link>/posts/project/optical-gating/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 13:29:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/project/optical-gating/</guid>
      <description>Developing a smart microscopy system for imaging the beating zebrafish heart over extended periods of time. &lt;a href=&#34;/project/optical-gating/index.html&#34;&gt;Read more&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Nuclei Detection</title>
      <link>/posts/project/nuclei-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 13:29:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/project/nuclei-detection/</guid>
      <description>Using mathematical techniques to automatically detect and quantify nuclei in 2D and 3D bioimaging data. &lt;a href=&#34;/project/nuclei-detection/index.html&#34;&gt;Read more&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imaging the Developing Eye</title>
      <link>/posts/project/zebrafish-retinal-microscopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 13:29:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/project/zebrafish-retinal-microscopy/</guid>
      <description>Using advanced optics to minimise abberations when imaging the developing zebrafish eye. &lt;a href=&#34;/project/zebrafish-retinal-microscopy/index.html&#34;&gt;Read more&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object-based Colocalisation</title>
      <link>/posts/project/object-based-colocalisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 13:29:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/project/object-based-colocalisation/</guid>
      <description>Using object-based colocalisation to quantify the interactions between protein structures in cellular biology. &lt;a href=&#34;/project/object-based-colocalisation/index.html&#34;&gt;Read more&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantiative Calcium Imaging</title>
      <link>/posts/project/quantitative-calcium-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 13:29:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/project/quantitative-calcium-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Investigating volumetric and computational imaging approaches for accurately measuring calcium signals between neurons. &lt;a href=&#34;/project/quantitative-calcium-imaging/index.html&#34;&gt;Read more&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retinal Vessel Enhancement</title>
      <link>/posts/project/retinal-image-enhancement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 13:29:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/project/retinal-image-enhancement/</guid>
      <description>Using mathematical approaches to enhance images for improved vessel extraction. &lt;a href=&#34;/project/retinal-image-enhancement/index.html&#34;&gt;Read more&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Culture: Changing Expectations</title>
      <link>/posts/the-little-eye/research-culture-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 14:54:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-little-eye/research-culture-2/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s now been two weeks since I attended the Royal Society&amp;rsquo;s Research Culture - Changing Expectations meeting and it&amp;rsquo;s amazing how many topics from the meetings have come up organically in conversations with other academics, particularly early career researchers. I&amp;rsquo;ve already written about a few of these in my earlier post and in this post I&amp;rsquo;ll summarise some key topics from the second day.
As mentioned in my last post this and my last post are a brief summary of just some of the ideas and messages that particularly spoke to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Culture: Changing Expectations</title>
      <link>/posts/the-little-eye/research-culture-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 11:43:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-little-eye/research-culture-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week (29-30th October 2018) I attended a meeting at the Royal Society (London) with an aim of considering the UK scientific research culture - identifying challenges, highlighting best practice and considering what the future UK research culture can and should be. This meeting is a culmination of a two year programme of events and consultations (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://royalsociety.org/topics-policy/projects/research-culture/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting was full of inspiring speakers and great ideas and this and my next post are a really very brief summary of just some of the ideas and messages that particularly spoke to me. I have referenced speakers throughout but some of these points may be my own interpretation and opinion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imaging the Beating Heart in Zebrafish</title>
      <link>/posts/the-little-eye/imaging-the-beating-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 17:12:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-little-eye/imaging-the-beating-heart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2018 has been a busy year so far (and I expect it will stay that way) but I’ve finally made time to write another blog post (and also to move my blog into my personal website). Given that so far this year I’ve spoken about my current research - imaging the beating zebrafish heart - to audiences of academics, the public &amp;amp; students I thought it was about time to do a blog post summarising said research. Hopefully this short post will provide you with an idea of what we’re trying to achieve, why and how we’re going about it (although I&amp;rsquo;ve kept off too much detail for now).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better Imaging of Living Animals and the 3Rs</title>
      <link>/posts/the-little-eye/better-imaging-and-the-3rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 16:04:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-little-eye/better-imaging-and-the-3rs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I was explaining my research to another academic from a different field. I was describing how, when imaging living animals under the microscope, we strive to keep laser power levels to the minimum needed. The question I got in return was: &amp;ldquo;Is that for the animal&amp;rsquo;s sake or for the imaging?&amp;rdquo;. And of course the answer is both - in general, I find that good science and better microscopy align very well with performing more humane animal research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is about how researchers are working to improve animal research by minimising numbers used, sharing animals and data and refining experimental procedures.  This is not an article on whether or not animal experimentation should or should not be done; that is a matter of personal ethics. However, should you be interested in the rules and regulations surrounding animal research in the UK, I would suggest you start with Understanding Animal Research &lt;a href=&#34;#understanding&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; and the National Centre for the Replacement, Refinement and Reduction of Animals in Research (the NC3RS) &lt;a href=&#34;#nc3rs&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let There be Light... but Not Too Much</title>
      <link>/posts/the-little-eye/phototoxicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 18:19:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-little-eye/phototoxicity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;light-is-an-essential-aspect-of-microscopy&#34;&gt;Light is an Essential Aspect of Microscopy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An essential aspect to microscopy is light. Early microscopes used ambient light or used mirrors to reflect light, either from the sun or a candle, onto the sample of interest. With the inventions &lt;a href=&#34;#bulb&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; of the electric light bulb additional, artificial light sources could be used and the light from lamps could be focussed onto samples with much greater control.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microscopes on Your Mobile Phone</title>
      <link>/posts/the-little-eye/mobile-phone-microscopes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 15:30:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-little-eye/mobile-phone-microscopes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many modern microscopes can be large, highly technical and expensive pieces of equipment. This is most evidenced when you consider that, when funding such equipment at UK universities and research institutes, many funding bodies stipulate a requirement for sharing across multiple research groups or institutes. However, as developers of new microscopy technology a focus on such fancy and costly microscopes should not be at the detriment of the continued research into miniaturisation, cheaper manufacturing and improved transportable microscopes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D Segmentation Techniques</title>
      <link>/posts/project/3d-segmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/project/3d-segmentation/</guid>
      <description>Using active meshes and level set methods for improved 3D segmentation. &lt;a href=&#34;/project/3d-segmentation/index.html&#34;&gt;Read more&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
