<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>academia on Chas Nelson</title>
    <link>/categories/academia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in academia on Chas Nelson</description>
    <image>
      <url>cjn.jpg</url>
      <link>cjn.jpg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 14:54:38 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/academia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Research Culture: Changing Expectations</title>
      <link>/posts/the-little-eye/research-culture-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 14:54:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-little-eye/research-culture-2/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s now been two weeks since I attended the Royal Society&amp;rsquo;s Research Culture - Changing Expectations meeting and it&amp;rsquo;s amazing how many topics from the meetings have come up organically in conversations with other academics, particularly early career researchers. I&amp;rsquo;ve already written about a few of these in my earlier post and in this post I&amp;rsquo;ll summarise some key topics from the second day.
As mentioned in my last post this and my last post are a brief summary of just some of the ideas and messages that particularly spoke to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Culture: Changing Expectations</title>
      <link>/posts/the-little-eye/research-culture-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 11:43:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-little-eye/research-culture-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week (29-30th October 2018) I attended a meeting at the Royal Society (London) with an aim of considering the UK scientific research culture - identifying challenges, highlighting best practice and considering what the future UK research culture can and should be. This meeting is a culmination of a two year programme of events and consultations (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://royalsociety.org/topics-policy/projects/research-culture/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting was full of inspiring speakers and great ideas and this and my next post are a really very brief summary of just some of the ideas and messages that particularly spoke to me. I have referenced speakers throughout but some of these points may be my own interpretation and opinion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standing up for Science</title>
      <link>/posts/the-little-eye/standing-up-for-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 20:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-little-eye/standing-up-for-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I attended the Sense about Science &lt;a href=&#34;#sas&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; media workshop: Standing up for Science &lt;a href=&#34;#workshop&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;. The day is run as part of their Voice of Young Science network &lt;a href=&#34;#voys&#34;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; and aims to help early career scientists launch themselves into the rather intimidating field of media engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop itself was a really interesting day so thanks to Chris Peters and Ana Skamarauskas for organising and chairing through the day. It was primarily composed of three very interactive panels: scientists who have communicated with the media, journalists who work in STEM-related media, and the &amp;rsquo;nuts and bolts&amp;rsquo; panel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let There be Light... but Not Too Much</title>
      <link>/posts/the-little-eye/phototoxicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 18:19:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-little-eye/phototoxicity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;light-is-an-essential-aspect-of-microscopy&#34;&gt;Light is an Essential Aspect of Microscopy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An essential aspect to microscopy is light. Early microscopes used ambient light or used mirrors to reflect light, either from the sun or a candle, onto the sample of interest. With the inventions &lt;a href=&#34;#bulb&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; of the electric light bulb additional, artificial light sources could be used and the light from lamps could be focussed onto samples with much greater control.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Touching Life</title>
      <link>/posts/the-little-eye/technology-touching-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 21:29:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-little-eye/technology-touching-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This Tuesday (the 20th June 2017) I attended a workshop on the new &lt;em&gt;Technology Touching Life&lt;/em&gt; scheme being run by three of the UK&amp;rsquo;s research councils &lt;a href=&#34;#ttl&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;. The workshops (this was the last of three) were run jointly by the Biotechnology and Biological Sciences Research Council (BBSRC), the Engineering and Physical Sciences Reseasrch Council (EPSRC) and the Medical Research Council (MRC) to foster multidisciplinary and interdisciplinary networks and better integrate such research into the often disciplinary nature of the research councils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the current changes in the research council structure, and the regularly recognised important of multidisciplinary research at this interface, can we expect to see a change in how the councils work together for better multidisciplinary research across the UK?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
